Peter Ayello-Wright

3 Cardinals Ways, Ely, CB4 2GF

Mobile: 07976 219 529 Email: peter.ayellowright@gmail.com www.peterayellowright.co.uk

Personal Profile

Accountancy graduate from the University of Portsmouth, with experience working in a wide range of industries, gaining experience in data analysis, customer service and hospitality. I first gained an interest in development from my time working for booking.com and regularly attended seminars where we discussed User Experience innovations and future developments of the business. It was at this time that I started to learn to code using Python from online resources such as Lynda, Codecademy and edX in my spare time.

Currently pursuing my passion to work in development by partaking in a self-funded IT course with Just IT. The course is assisting me in a more structured way to learn the skills to commence my journey as a developer. I am in the process of creating projects including developing a CRUD blog using PHP Laravel. I have also created websites for family and my soul band.

For the future, I am looking to continue learning in a PHP developer role. I am keen to get stuck in, I understand the challenges the role faces and know that I have the ability and desire to succeed.

Education and IT Training

May 2016-Present Just IT Training Ltd, London

Development Professional Programme

- MTA Software Development Fundamentals (Expected 2017)
- MTA HTML5 Web Application Development Fundamentals (Expected 2017)
- MCSD Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (Expected 2017)

2013 Chartered Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA)

2013 ClMA Dip MA - CIMA diploma in Management Accounting Chartered Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA)

CIMA Cert BA - Certificate of Business Accounting

2010 University of Portsmouth

BA(Hons) Accounting 2:2

Dissertation: Was nationalisation an effective approach for the banking

crisis in UK (2007-2010)

2003 - 2005 Colchester Sixth Form College

A Levels: Mathematics, Music, Business Studies

2003 Stoke College, Suffolk

GCSE: 9 GCSEs A - C including Maths and English

IT Skills

Web Technology: Created portfolio using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and Bootstrap.

Core Programming Languages: PHP, Laravel, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and MySQL

Employment History

09/2017 Studio 24, Cambridge, UK - Intern

- I gained a contact from attending the PHP coding Meetup in Cambridge. I was given 2 weeks exposure to life in a digital agency.
- Assisted with the production of their intranet built with PHP Laravel adding new functionalities.
- Followed best practise coding standards and strictly worked with git version control.
- Gained experience creating new sites and modifying older sites built in PHP WordPress, Drupal, Zend and Laravel.

- Volunteering remotely for an ambitious charity based in California that's aim is to spread happiness throughout the world by doing good deeds. Their main focus at the moment is www.thegoodcards.com which is an IoT concept based on doing a good deed passing on a Good Card and spreading it across the world.
- My role is to assist with the development and creation of landing pages for the charity using WordPress and CornerStone and to collate, analyse and present the Google Analytics data in the weekly meeting. All sites are connected to web marketing campaigns and I implement active-Campaign on all sites through ConvertPlug. I regularly make multiple pages with slight differences that are then A/B tested for their effectiveness using Google Analytics and ConvertPlug.

02/2017 - Present Born to be Beautiful, Cambridge WordPress Developer

- Volunteering with a local charity in my spare time. Adding and modifying content to their Word-Press website to improve the User Experience.
- Gaining experiencing with a working CMS with the objective of improving the SEO, implementing analytics and improving the User Experience.
- Assisting with other technology related items such as editing videos on the video blog, and updating social media sites Facebook and Twitter.

09/2016 - Present ARM Ltd, Cambridge Payroll Assistant

- Assisting with the accurate and timely production of payroll for the EMEA operations of ARM Ltd.
- Creating and implementing new automated systems for payroll using MS Excel to remove manual checking and increase efficiency and accuracy.
- Creating reports for EMEA HR department to increase accuracy of company records using MS Excel and SAP ECC HANA.

05/2015 - 05/2016 Crunch Catering, London Sous Chef

- A role that required working long hours, in a small team, to strict deadlines to ensure that breakfast, lunch and tea were always delivered on time and to a high standard.
- Communicating with the heads of department and production to ensure that more unusual filming locations were acted upon when planning menus.

Management Information Assistant

05/2014 - 10/2014 Muntons plc, Suffolk

- Working in the FP&A team of a manufacturing business to produce KPI reports for the entire business supply chain by extracting data from SAP and manipulating it using complex formulae in MS Excel; ensuring the reports were ready for the monthly management meeting.
- Created reports to show the monthly performance of the sales managers and directors, using MS Excel and data warehousing software.
- Updated and maintained an SQL server database, used by customer service department to create and modify deliveries. Conducted regular meetings with the Customer Service Managers to discuss any required improvements or modifications.
- Creating ad-hoc sales reports for sales managers and directors with the objective of assisting business development.
- Created a program in MS Excel using VBA and Macros for the warehouse to create order information.

03/2014 The Silver Spoon Company, Suffolk Finance Assignment

- 4-week internship working closely with the finance manager to learn accountancy processes and key MS Excel techniques (filters, V/HLookup, SUMIFS and IF formulae, PivotTables, Concatenations and INDEX formulae)
- Conducting several projects to cut costs within the business such as negotiating a cost-saving measure on staff food and drink using MS Excel and SAP ECC6 data.

11/2012 - 03/2014 Booking.com, Cambridge Customer Service Executive

- Liaising between the customers and clients, modifying reservations, handling special requests and complaints by phone and e-mails.
- Working to targets for performance (resolving 10 cases an hour); customer satisfaction (90% customer satisfaction on customer questionnaires) and quality (ensuring that we are working closely to company procedures)
- Awarded "Office Hero" for training and mentoring colleagues out of 400 employees in the office.

Interests and Achievements

Computing: I first became interested in programming whilst working for <u>booking.com</u> where I would regularly attend innovation workshops to offer ideas to improve the user experience. I subsequently under-

took Lynda, edX, Codecademy and freecodecamp courses in HTML/CSS, JavaScript and Python in my own time before deciding to pursue IT professionally.

Hobbies: I am a keen musician and teach guitar and play bass guitar in a soul/funk band with the objective of playing parties and weddings in the near future. I also enjoy keeping fit with running and cycling. I continue to cook and enjoy creating new recipes. I enjoy doing mathematical coding exercises and problems to further my understanding of programming applications.

References Available Upon Request